## PETER BAGGETTA B.ENG

(416)854-5405 \( \phi\) peter.baggetta@gmail.com \( \phi\) github.com/PeterBaggetta \( \phi\) https://peterbaggetta.com/

#### **PROFILE**

As a Computer Engineer, who graduated in April 2023 I bring current knowledge and strong problem-solving skills to the workforce. With a strong work ethic and self-motivation, I am a dependable worker who is committed to completing tasks correctly and effectively. My experience working in an office environment, in logistics, as a developer, and in the public sector, has equipped me with the ability to communicate principles clearly and effectively. These skills are valuable assets in any work environment, allowing me to collaborate and contribute in a meaningful way, while working towards my P.Eng. licence.

# SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

- 4 years Git, GitHub & GitLab
- 4 years HTML & CSS, C & C++
- 4 years MATLAB & Simulink & R
- 3 years Python, Java & JavaScript
- 3 years Verilog, VHDL & assembly
- 3 years NodeJS, React & React Native
- 2 years PHP, SQL & NoSQL, Spring Boot, React, Junit, Jira, Figma & Cloudflare
- 1 year Microsoft Azure, Docker, Bitbucket, Cloudinary & SwiftUI

- AWS Solutions Architect Knowledge Badge (AWS Cloud Technologies)
- Quartus, Vivado, Cadence, & Xilinx
- Windows, Mac & Linux experience
- FreeRTOS, I2C, SPI, ARM Cortex
- FPGAs and SoC Device (ARM & x86) programming in VHDL, Verilog, MIPS/ARM assembly & C
- Keil & IAR Compiler workflow

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Development Engineering Intern, Publicis Sapient

Toronto, Ontario

JUNE 2022 – AUGUST 2022

- Developed a powerful, full-stack web application using Spring Boot, React and NodeJS.
- To construct and serve the application, Bitbucket, REST, CI/CD Pipelines, Docker Containers, Kubernetes, and MongoDB were utilized.
- Containerized the application using Docker and Bitbucket, ensuring continuous integration and deployment with Microsoft Azure.
- The platform created was instrumental in attracting \$1 billion in media sales.
- Worked collaboratively in an engineering team environment with skilled full-stack developers and internal project managers.
- Maintained professional relationships with the partner company, ensuring that the product met their requirements by holding weekly meetings using the Agile process.

#### **Supply Chain Intern,** Bernstein Diet & Health Clinics

Toronto, Ontario

- Leveraged the in-house software to track medical orders, ensuring their timely delivery.
- Provided valuable suggestions to improve the usability and accessibility of the company's software, which was well received by the IT department.
- Worked on computer hardware upgrades and assisted in migrating system to new operating systems.
- Supported the fulfillment of online orders during a busy season, on average completed over 200 orders per day.
- Worked in an office environment to collaborate closely with the IT department, sharing ideas for software improvements. Validated and tested newly launched software before releasing it to the rest of the internal employees, ensuring its success.
- Experienced in logistics and software management and skills necessary to excel in a fast-paced and dynamic work environment.

MAY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

### Landscaping/Maintenance Team, Copper Creek

Toronto, Ontario

MAY 2020 – PRESENT

- Worked in a senior role within the landscaping team to maintain the conditions of the land
- Trained new employees to utilize different equipment around the workplace.
- Helped streamline the training process for new employees and helped improve the efficiency for services while offering day-to-day support.
- Informed fellow coworkers on WHMIS safety measures and protocols along with proper PPE when working with heavy machinery.
- Kept an orderly and clean workspace while following all guidelines and expectations needed to ensure quality conditions for the golf course.

#### Lifeguard & Swim Instructor, University of Guelph

Guelph, Ontario

SEPTEMBER 2019 – FEBRUARY 2023

- Ensured the safety and well-being of a diverse group of over 200 guests within and around the swimming pools, maintaining constant vigilance and attentiveness.
- Engaged with patrons by offering valuable swimming tips and techniques specifically catering to individuals with limited swimming abilities, assisting them in gaining confidence and comfort in the water.
- Demonstrated leadership skills by taking charge during challenging situations involving fellow patrons or lifeguard colleagues, effectively resolving conflicts, and ensuring a harmonious pool environment.
- Collaborated with a diverse range of learners, parents, and fellow staff members to address individual needs, monitor progress, and create and inclusive and supporting learning environment.

#### PROJECTS

#### **AES Encryption Coprocessor in CBC Mode**

- Implemented an AES co-processor on a DE1-SoC development board, which uses an Altera SoC with dual-core Cortex A-9 embedded cores.
- The project was developed using Verilog and C code within the Quartus Prime II FPGA Software IDE.

### Data Compression in an Edge Computing Environment using an Auto-Encoder

- Developed a data compression auto-encoder in Python and C to measure CPU performance and power consumption.
- Assessed the efficiency of the encoder within an edge computing environment and figured out ways to optimize compile and runtime using different compilers.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelors of Computer Engineering**, University of Guelph

Guelph, Ontario

SEPTEMBER 2019 – APRIL 2023

- Graduated with High Honours
- Dean's List, 4 consecutive semesters